Vanessa Gonzales

Dubai Marina, Dubai, UAE · GonzalesVG@hotmail.com · +971 55 921 1120



Strategic and results-driven business leader with 10+ years of consulting and client services experience, specialized in project management, organizational change and implementation of large-scale business and technology solutions using agile methodologies; motivated by breaking down complex issues and objectives to simplified processes and sustainable results.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Project Management & Governance
- Client Relationship Management
- Change Management
- Business Process Design, Process Improvement
- Training Development & Delivery
- Master Data Management & Analysis
- Risk Identification & Mitigation
- Product & Software Lifecycle Design and Implementation
- Business Development
- Executive Level Presentation
- Team Management & Team Building
- Global, Multi-cultural, Cross-functional Collaboration

WORK EXPERIENCE

KALYPSO LP, Dubai, UAE

September 2014 - Present

Management consulting firm specializing in innovation strategy and Product Lifecycle Management (PLM) Primary industries served: FMCG, Food & Beverage, Healthcare, Medical Devices and Retail

Manager (2016-Present)

- Dedicated Project Manager of 30+ person team for large-scale Global PLM solution design & implementation, managed all aspects of the project including workplans, stakeholder management, system & process design, testing and user adoption
- Identified additional business development opportunities for client project extension and value adding services resulting in 3.5 years of contract and statements of work extensions with existing clients
- Implemented Global PLM tools and processes end-to-end across 27 markets and R&D centers throughout AMENA (Asia, Middle East, North Africa) business unit enabling centralized BU management of raw materials, vendors and finished goods
- Led communication strategy & management between Executive PLM Program leadership in USA and AMENA function teams including R&D, Innovation, Supply Chain, Procurement and IT within each market
- Led stakeholder and impact analysis of PLM data flow, business processes and organizational design requirements for consolidation to Global Standardized Operating Procedures (SOPs)
- Investigated project risks and requirements to ensure adequate resourcing, change management and leadership alignment to support activity iterations and overall transformation
- Applied agile methodologies to the design of a product data management platform; Developed detailed transition plan for all global divisions, ensuring a successful go-live, end-user system adoption, and downstream manufacturing system integration
- Developed dashboards to track progress against KPIs; Presented weekly and monthly project status to client's leadership and governance teams for stakeholder decision escalation while managing client's expectations and requirements
- Developed end-user training courses, training materials and led training sessions for 500+ R&D end users onsite across Asia & Europe for go-live and adoption of a new Product Change Management platform and globally standardized procedures

Senior Consultant (2014-2016)

- Devised and implemented a data migration strategy for raw material and finished product specification data from legacy to new PLM system; led data quality & governance processes for successful data migration meeting R&D, IT and system requirements
- Developed business-cases and change requests for a global PLM design solution to address market specific business process needs and product data requirements to ensure product compliance with local market regulations throughout Europe and Asia

GE CAPITAL- Experienced Commercial Leadership Program (ECLP), Dallas, TX

2013

Global rotational MBA work program for marketing and sales leadership development

MBA Leadership Program

- Designed and executed the first annual NPS/Voice of Customer survey program for GE Capital's Vendor Finance business; analyzed data to make strategic recommendations for enhanced go-to market planning and marketing strategies
- Created a global pricing strategy for part sales in the Oil & Gas Global Services business; pricing analysis identified \$1.9M
 immediate opportunity in global price changes and pricing alignment
- Launched and led a committee to develop an internal ECLP domain for consolidation of GE's dispersed marketing tools and ECLP
 program resources to benefit and support the global ECLP community development across all GE divisions globally

Vanessa Gonzales

Dubai Marina, Dubai, UAE · GonzalesVG@hotmail.com · +971 55 921 1120

KPMG LLP, Dallas, TX

2006-2012

Risk Consulting- Internal Audit, Risk & Compliance Services

Primary industries served: FMCG, Healthcare, Manufacturing, Real Estate, Retail

Senior Associate (2008-2012)

- Specialized in data-driven process improvement and internal audit engagements; executed 15 projects throughout the U.S. and abroad including Canada, Chile, China, Costa Rica, Mexico, Russia, and Scotland
- Led teams of 2-8 people to perform financial risk data assessments and client interviews to map current state business processes, presented findings to client stakeholders on process gaps and risk mitigated future state process recommendations
- Developed internal control testing approaches resulting in significant audit cost reduction and improved resource allocation, streamlining the client's Sarbanes-Oxley (SOX) 404 compliance audit procedures
- Designed global procedures and tools for risk analysis of financial ERP system's Segregation of Duty (SOD) conflicts; led WebEx trainings to 14 Country Finance Managers on tools for SOD risk identification and mitigation methods for respective home country business units
- Conducted data-driven assessments to identify complex data anomalies and financial fraud indicators; resulted in fraud detection findings and previously unidentified significant business risk exposure critical to the organization's objectives
- Contributed to sales initiatives including writing responses for proposals, statements of work and building engagement revenue models

Associate (2006-2008)

- Developed skills in risk management, audit, and accounting operations while performing financial and IT internal control assessments in 17 clients across multiple industries
- Conducted three internal audits and two IT audits independently immediately after start date; executed projects on-time and in-budget which led to promotion

VAUGHAN SYSTEMS, Madrid, Spain

2005

Communications consultancy specializing in English business language training for business leaders

English Business Consultant

Consulted corporate executives in English language communication development;
 consistently improved client's workplace productivity and professional development

THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN, McCombs School of Business, Austin, TX

Grew client demand 20% by developing an 'English Business Intensive" course offering

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration, Full-Time Program

May 2014

- Specialization in Innovation Leadership and Global Business
- Elected VP of Finance for the Graduate Business Council and VP of Marketing for the Business Communications Club
- Teaching Assistant for the MBA Career Planning course and for the MBA Strategic Management course

THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN, College of Liberal Arts, Austin, TX December 2004 Bachelor of Arts in Sociology; International Business Foundations Certification

- London School of Economics International Marketing and Finance Program (Spring 2004 Study Abroad)
- University of Madrid Complutense International Business Management Program (Fall 2003 Study Abroad)

References available upon request

Professional Experience



Certification

Project Management Professional (PMP) Certification, Project Management Institute

Languages

English (Native)
Spanish (Advanced)
Arabic (A2, learning)

Applications

Advanced MS Excel, PowerPoint, Word, Visio Tableau Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop

Personal Interests

PADI certified Rescue Diver (Dive Master/Instructor certification in process)

Avid traveler and passionate about new and culturally diverse experiences (travelled to 39 countries, led work projects in 19 countries, lived in 4 countries)

Personal Details

Nationality: American, Spanish (dual)

Visa Status: Resident